BEATRIZ LIEVANO CABALLERO

305-807-1527

blievanocaballero@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

Strategic **Human Resources Executive** and proactive Human Resources Business Partner to senior policy-making and operations managers. Demonstrated effectiveness in providing vision and counsel in steering organizations through personnel challenges and the development of human capital. Diverse background includes experience in high level multi-disciplinary organizations in both the public and private sector. These organizations include large hospitals and insurance companies as well as state government.

Expertise in Human Resources Initiatives

Recruitment & Employment Management; Leadership Training & Development; Benefits & Compensation Design; Reorganization & Culture Change; Non-Union and Union Employee Relations; Succession Planning; Long-Range Business Planning; HR Policies & Procedures; Mergers and Acquisitions; ADP Payroll Processing System; SAP SuccessFactors

EXPERIENCE

State of Florida 2005-Present

Director, Human Resources, Florida Supreme Court- Office of the State Courts Administrator

Serve as chief Human Resources advisor to all Supreme Court Justices and senior level directors. Act as principal Human Resources liaison to all 5 District Courts of Appeal and 20 Circuit Trial Courts. Direct and manage statewide operations of Human Resources for the Florida State Courts System which includes approximately 4,000 employees. Responsible for staff supervision, strategic development of talent management, payroll and benefits, employee relations, employee engagement, performance management and investigation of harassment complaints. Travel throughout Florida offices to ensure compliance with Human Resources policies.

Director, Human Resource Management, Florida Department of Financial Services

Responsible for statewide operations of Recruitment, Benefits, Compensation, Payroll, Employee Engagement, and Training and Development. Directed Collective Bargaining negotiations in conjunction with state agencies. Monitored activities and made recommendations on matters affecting employees of the Department of Financial Services.

Human Resources Administrator, Florida Commission on Offender Review

Responsible for the operations of Recruitment, Benefits, Compensation, Training and EEO complaints. Confirmed that personnel matters complied with Florida statutory law and governing administrative code.

Affiliated Computer Services (ACS)

Human Resources Manager

Managed all operations within the human resources division; operations which included recruitment, compensation, benefits, employee counseling, any/all promotional or corrective personnel matters. Led employee counseling sessions in conjunction with the Washington, DC based corporate headquarters to ensure cross-jurisdictional consistency with all regional operations.

Blue Cross Blue Shield of North Carolina

1999-2001

2002-2005

Human Resources Generalist

Led human resources training seminars to assist in the creation of a well informed and capable team of employees. Partnered with senior management during the recruitment, retention and promotion of BCBS's workforce, and provided counsel during more challenging personnel matters.

Memorial Healthcare System

1996-1998

Human Resources Generalist

Assisted approximately 700 employees with all human resource matters including grievances, compensation, benefits and separation processes. Led cultural diversity training and new hire orientation. Attended unemployment appeals hearings; managed workers compensation cases and attended depositions when required.

EDUCATION

Florida International University, Miami, Florida *Bachelor of Business Administration*, 1992

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Trainer in Targeted Selection (Behavioral Interviewing) Development Dimensions International, Inc.

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Conversational proficiency and fluency)